hi spring fans welcome to another
嗨， Spring 粉丝们欢迎来到另一个
installment of spring tips in this
在此安装Spring 提示
installment of spring tips we're gonna
我们将要介绍的 spring 技巧
look at the new micrometer framework
看看新的千分尺框架
right so micrometer is a second is a
对，千分之一秒是一个
another project as a product that's
作为产品的另一个项目
independent of spring that is a been led
独立于被领导的 Spring
by pivotal but of course it's an open
通过关键，但当然是开放的
sort of projects and so enjoys
这类项目，所以很享受
contributions from a lot of different
来自许多不同的贡献
who want to make this the best tool for
谁想要使其成为最佳工具
their particular use case it is it mint
他们特殊的用例是薄荷
it is meant to be a vendor neutral
它意味着对供应商是中立的
application metrics facade and I really
应用程序指标外观，我真的
quite like this this description here
很像这里的描述
because it's quite fitting
因为很合适
it's like SL f4j but for metrics the
就像SL f4j，但对于指标
goal of this framework is to capture
该框架的目标是捕获
metrics and to publish them to time
指标并及时发布
series databases and monitoring systems
系列数据库和监控系统
things like Prometheus and Netflix's
像Prometheus和Netflix一样
Atlas and signal FX and wavefront and
图集和信号FX和波前以及
cloud watch and data dog and graphite
云手表，数据狗和石墨
and ganglia and JMX and influx DB and
和神经节，JMX和Influx DB以及
New Relic and stats T etc so a lot of
新的文物和统计资料T等很多
different times here's databases and
在不同的时间这里的数据库和
these databases are you know optimized
您知道这些数据库已经过优化
for managing keys and I use a key that
用于管理密钥，而我使用的是
you can then you know ascribe a number
您可以知道数字
to and the whole history of that number
到该数字的全部历史
so you can use these tools to graph the
因此您可以使用这些工具来绘制
trend of a number over time you can see
您可以看到一段时间内的数字趋势
for example the peaks and valleys you
例如您的山峰和山谷
can you can query that to see to drive
你可以查询一下来开车吗
to derive information to drive derive
推导信息以驱动推导
insight rather from the from the numbers
洞察力，而不是数字
and then to use that insight to drive
然后利用这些见识来推动
change in the code and you can also use
更改代码，您也可以使用
it for alerting you can use it for all
提醒您可以将其用于所有
sorts of things when it comes to your
关于您的事情
applications health and a lot of people
应用程序健康和很多人
turn to time series databases and
转到时间序列数据库并
monitoring tools like this to understand
这样的监控工具可以了解
latency to understand how information is
了解信息的延迟
performing how certain parts the
执行某些部分
applications are performing and so on
应用程序正在执行等等
metrics are meant to capture the
指标旨在捕获
aggregate the the sort of the aggregate
汇总汇总的种类
state of a particular exchange for
特定交换的状态
example not to capture individual
不捕获个人的例子
individual exchanges right so if I want
个人交流对，所以如果我想
to understand you know the average
了解你知道平均水平
latency for a call to an endpoint then
然后呼叫端点的等待时间
this is a great tool T to use for that
这是一个很棒的工具T
because I can sample all the different
因为我可以采样所有不同的
requests
要求
have gone to a ten point and I get a
已经到了十点，我得到了
number and then I can sum those up
数字，然后我可以总结一下
together divided by the number of
一起除以
samples and then there you go that's my
样品，然后去那是我的
that's my my average for example right
这就是我的平均水平，例如
metal and I can also use statistics to
金属，我也可以使用统计数据
look at all the numbers and arrive at
查看所有数字并得出
things like the the 95th percentile the
像第95个百分点
median right all these different
中位数对所有这些不同
interesting numbers that I want
我想要的有趣数字
understand when it comes latency if
了解延迟何时发生
however I want to look at a particular
但是我想看一个特定的
exchange as concerns me Josh then I made
交换有关我的事，乔希然后我做了
on the website you know a week ago and I
在一周前和我知道的网站上
want to see where that's where that
想看看那是哪里
request went and how long it took and so
请求去了，花了多长时间等等
on then this is the this is the wrong
在那这是错的
tool for the job in that case you'd use
在这种情况下，您将使用的工作工具
this to be tracing so metrics are good
这是要跟踪的，因此指标很好
for sort of ad to get big picture sort
进行广告分类以获得大图片
of numbers and they can help you
数字，它们可以帮助您
understand you know the the movement of
了解你知道的运动
data through the system and they can
数据通过系统，他们可以
help you understand all sorts of other
帮助您了解各种其他
things related to your applications
与您的应用有关的事情
state right so um it's very important to
说对了，所以对
have these defender systems in your
在您的系统中有这些防御系统
organization and a good platform of
组织和良好的平台
course like Cloud Foundry will stand up
当然像Cloud Foundry这样的站起来
and support these metrics automatically
并自动支持这些指标
out of the box so if you're using Cloud
开箱即用，所以如果您使用的是Cloud
Foundry there's a media registry
铸造厂有媒体注册处
implementation there that micrometer
在那里执行千分尺
will automatically integrate with so a
会自动与
lot of different a lot of different ways
很多不同很多不同的方式
to use this now this project is not as I
现在使用这个项目不是我
say it's not part of spring it's a
说这不是 Spring 的一部分，而是
separate project that can be used
可以使用的单独项目
independent of spring a number of
独立于Spring
different projects are already
已经有不同的项目
supporting and out of the box including
支持和开箱即用，包括
for example a car ACP I think I saw that
例如汽车ACP，我想我看到了
they're gonna have micrometer metrics
他们将有千分尺
publication built into the code itself
代码本身内置的出版物
the rabbitmq Java client will support
rabbitmq Java客户端将支持
this I mean you know you you know we're
我的意思是你知道你知道我们
seeing more proliferation of mccomber in
看到mccomber在
different Java projects it is being used
正在使用不同的Java项目
like slf Virginia or log4j or some sort
如slf Virginia或log4j或其他某种形式
of library like that where it's just
像这样的图书馆
embedded you just have to to work with
嵌入式，您只需要使用
it you know it'll it'll it'll be a
如果你知道，它将是一个
common sort of currency for this kind of
常见的这种货币
use case now why this why a micrometer
现在用例为什么这为什么要用千分尺
instead of something like for example
而不是像
drop Wizard metrics well the answer is
很好地删除向导指标，答案是
first of all in some cases we're still
首先，在某些情况下，我们仍然
using the dropper xored metric libraries
使用滴管异或度量库
but the larger answer is that this
但是更大的答案是
supersedes the drop wizard metrics
取代放置向导指标
library because it supports dimensional
库，因为它支持维
metrics right there's the big big thing
指标是一件大事
right here the the the biggest feature
这里最大的特点
here is this idea of just dimensional
这就是维的想法
metric so when we talk about dimensional
指标，所以当我们谈论尺寸时
metrics
指标
we need to just just you know
我们只需要你知道
distinguish that from hierarchical
区别于分层
metrics so let's say I open up this file
指标，所以假设我打开了此文件
here ok so now I've got let's say I want
好的，现在我要说我想要
to capture all of the HTML requests so
捕获所有HTML请求，因此
I'll say HTTP that requests this is a
我会说请求这的HTTP是一个
hierarchical metric right I can capture
我可以捕获的分级指标权利
this and each time there's a new request
每次有新要求时
I can +1 that count or I can keep the
我可以对该计数+1，也可以保留
duration of that or whatever well let's
持续时间或其他任何条件，让我们
say I also want to now capture all of
说我也想现在捕获所有
the requests that were ACB get and I
ACB收到的请求和我
want to also distinguish that from all
也想将其与众不同
those that were actually post and let's
那些实际上是张贴的，让我们
say I also want to get I want to also
说我也想得到我也想得到
distinguish that from the from the those
区别于那些
requests that had JSON so I have to now
具有JSON的请求，所以我现在
add JSON versus XML right and then let's
正确添加JSON和XML，然后让我们
say I also want to capture the the
说我也想捕捉
region right the region in which the
区域在其中
request was made you know the which
发出了请求，您知道哪个
instance of which servers got them maybe
哪些服务器得到了它们的实例
I've got servers in different cloud
我的服务器在不同的云中
provider regions like a US East and u.s.
美国东部和我们这样的提供者地区
West so I can say us let's see what's
西方，所以我可以说让我们看看是什么
the right way to do it I guess I can say
正确的方法我想我可以说
US East right down here as well and this
美国东部也就在这里
might be us West so it gets ready just
可能是我们西部，所以就准备好了
to break these apart and ideally I'd
打破这些，理想情况下，我会
have to maintain you know to be able to
必须保持你知道的能力
most efficiently query this kind of data
最有效地查询此类数据
in a non hierarchical system I'd have to
在非分层系统中，我必须
maintain different counts write
保持不同的计数写
different numbers different metrics for
不同的数字，不同的指标
all of this to build to drill down so
所有这些都是为了深入挖掘
I'd have to say here's the count of all
我不得不说这是全部
those that were posts and JSON here's
那些是帖子和JSON的
the count of all those that were in u.s.
所有在我们里面的人的数量
West they were posts and JSON right so
West他们是帖子和JSON，所以
it gets very hard to there's a
很难有一个
proliferation of services of metrics
指标服务的激增
that it becomes hard to manage now what
现在变得很难管理什么
if instead you could say ok I'm gonna
如果相反，你可以说好，我要
have one metric called HTML requests and
有一个指标称为HTML请求，
I'll have tags tags that give me extra
我将拥有标签标签，这些标签会给我额外
information they enrich that metric but
信息丰富了该指标，但
they aren't the metric in themselves
他们本身不是指标
things like oh the region is Us East and
哦，该地区是美国东部，
the method is get and you know the
方法是获取，您知道
content type is whatever I mean you know
内容类型就是我想知道的
JSON right so you can do all sorts of
正确的JSON，因此您可以进行各种
things there and in a hierarchical
那里的东西和一个层次
system it's not as easy to kind of model
系统不是那么容易建立模型
this kind of complex multi-dimensional
这种复杂的多维
data and it's certainly not as easy to
数据，当然不是那么容易
query it well a dimensional data you
很好地查询您的尺寸数据
know time series database like net
像网络一样了解时间序列数据库
listen and Prometheus will make querying
听，普罗米修斯将进行查询
and interacting with this kind of data a
并与此类数据进行交互
breeze so we we support that with this
微风，所以我们对此表示支持
API where appropriate now that said some
现在适当的地方说一些
ap some systems like Gen X don't support
ap某些系统，例如Gen X不支持
that you'll find that micrometer
你会发现千分尺
actually delegates to in this case the
实际上在这种情况下委托给
drop wizard metric support for JMX so
对JMX的拖放向导指标支持，因此
with that in place that's what that
有了那个就是那个
basic understanding of this stinkin
对这种臭味的基本了解
let's go ahead and build an application
让我们继续构建一个应用程序
we're gonna go ahead and build an
我们将继续建立一个
application as usual by going to start
像往常一样开始申请
that spring that IO and we'll build a
那年 Spring ，IO，我们将建立一个
new application here that uses spring
这里使用spring的新应用
boot to that oh and the actuator will
启动到哦，执行器将
use h2 JPA the web support and Lombok ok
使用H2 JPA Web支持和Lombok可以
now I'm going to call this demo
现在我要叫这个演示
micrometer and we're gonna hit generate
千分尺，我们要点击生成
and those give us a new project I'm
这些给了我们一个新的项目
going to open this up in our IDE as
将在我们的IDE中打开它
always and this project is going to just
总是，这个项目将只是
we're not gonna actually use all those
我们实际上不会使用所有这些
things we're not gonna build a web app
我们不会构建网络应用程序的东西
or talk to you know a 2jp or do a data
或与您交谈了解2jp或进行数据
source I just want to demonstrate that
来源我只想证明
this stuff is all automatically
这些东西都是自动的
instrumented for you so before we get
为您装备，所以在我们得到之前
into that though let's um let's look at
虽然，让我们来看看
the API the micrometer API independent
API千分尺API独立
of spring boots so just for now ignore
spring boot ，所以现在暂时忽略
the fact that this is a spring would
这是 Spring 的事实
application let's suppose I have this
假设我有这个
endpoint here and we'll create a new
终结点，我们将创建一个新的
endpoint when I create a new micrometer
创建新的千分尺时的终点
project independent of spring boot and
独立于Spring Boot和
the way you do that is you use a meter
您这样做的方式是使用电表
registry the immune registry is the
注册表是免疫注册表
heart of the API now in the spring boot
spring boot 时，API的核心
world this will be automatically
世界，这将是自动的
configured for you so you can just
为您配置，因此您可以
inject it you know what you want there
注入它，你知道你想要什么
are different implementations of media
是媒体的不同实现
registry you can see that we've got a
注册表，您可以看到我们有一个
composite meter registry a simple meter
复合电表注册表
area step you know register et cetera
您知道要注册的区域步骤等
I know drop wizard magic meter registry
我知道拖放向导魔术计注册表
which is just an adapter so I mean is a
这只是一个适配器，所以我的意思是
composite meter you know registry and
您知道注册表的复合表和
the composite composite mean a registry
复合复合意味着注册表
then has a chain of other meter
然后有其他仪表链
registries and these are registry
注册表，这些都是注册表
specific adapters if you will so here
特定的适配器，如果您会在这里
we're gonna go I want to say let's use
我们要走了，我想说让我们使用
micrometer registry Prometheus and the
千分尺注册表Prometheus和
version of course will be micrometer
版本当然是千分尺
version this is the property that's in
版本，这是其中的属性
spring boots so all this is you know
spring boot ，这就是你知道的
being managed for me by spring mood
Spring 的心情为我管理
thankfully don't have to manage that I'm
幸好不必管我
gonna use jmx as well so I have jmx and
还要使用jmx，所以我有jmx和
Prometheus and I'm gonna do is I'm going
普罗米修斯，我要做的就是我要去
to say to the Registrar so me to
对书记官长说，以便我
registry dad
注册表爸爸
new JMX made a registry and I could
新的JMX做了一个注册表，我可以
configure the config but I'm not gonna
配置配置，但我不会
bother running this code it want you to
麻烦运行此代码，让您
see kind of what's happening here new
看看这里发生了什么
Prometheus meter registry and all again
Prometheus仪表注册表以及所有这些
right so now we have two different
对，所以现在我们有两个不同的
states now we can use it in terms of the
声明现在我们可以根据
media registry interface so meter
媒体注册表界面
registry M R equals meter industry and
注册局MR等于电表行业
we can say e mr dot config we can
我们可以说e mr dot config我们可以
configure things that are common to all
配置所有人都通用的东西
filters or to all metrics in the system
过滤器或系统中的所有指标
we can say common tags for example
我们可以说例如常见标签
equals let's say region let's say I want
等于说地区，说我想要
to resolve that property get the
解决该财产得到
property here from you know cloud region
你知道这里的云区域
right everywhere so I'm pulling in that
就在任何地方，所以我要加入
region property from the environment
来自环境的区域属性
variable and that's gonna preface its
变量，这将作为其序言
give me a dimension it's gonna be a tag
给我一个尺寸，它将成为一个标签
that's gonna be added to every single
那将被添加到每一个
metric let's calculate collected in this
指标让我们计算一下
in this application once I've done that
在这个应用程序中，一旦完成
I can now start collecting metrics using
我现在可以开始使用收集指标
different types of meters and at the top
不同类型的仪表和顶部
level using the meter Registry type
液位计使用注册表类型
there are three types of meters there's
有三种类型的仪表
a counter which is a number that
一个计数器是一个数字
increments decrements over time so
随时间增加递减，因此
stepwise plus 1 or plus 10 or plus 5 so
逐步加1或加10或加5所以
you know I'm orders placed and I can
你知道我下订单了，我可以
then increment it or I can increment it
然后增加它，或者我可以增加它
by you know whatever I didn't do or just
你知道我什么都没做或只是
increment by one I can also increment it
加一我也可以加
by negative 2 123 right I can do
负2 123对，我可以做
decrements in that way I can create
以这种方式减少我可以创建
gauges a gauge is a a thing that has a
量规是具有
bounded value so a common example is
有界值，所以一个常见的例子是
they the gauge for speed in the car the
他们衡量汽车的速度
speedometer will show you that you you
车速表会告诉你你
know you can go from 1 to 120 for
知道你可以从1到120
example hundred 20 miles per hour here
例如每小时每小时20英里
in the States and that that's a bound
在美国，那是必然的
it's an upper bound your cars
这是你的车的上限
electronically limited or mechanically
电子限制或机械限制
limited in some way so as to stop you
以某种方式限制以阻止你
from going any faster than that the
比任何事情都快
result is that whatever speed you're
结果就是无论您的速度如何
going it's going to be some number in
将会有一些数字
between 0 and that and then upper bound
在0和那之间，然后是上限
so a gauge is a great great thing if
因此，如果
you're just having you're just trying to
你只是在试图
capture the fluctuating state of a
捕捉一个波动的状态
number in that in that range
该范围内的数字
okay so speed could be you know I'm
好吧，速度可能就是你知道我
going 12 right now it couldn't be going
现在要十二点了
55 whatever so I can capture it over
55无论如何，我可以将其捕获
time
时间
each time I capture this will be
每次我捕捉到这将是
recorded in the time series database
记录在时间序列数据库中
right or in the the registry of some
权利或在某些注册表中
sort and then finally we have a timer
排序，然后最后我们有了一个计时器
and timers are for my money are the most
计时器是我最大的花销
useful thing we can get out of a metrics
我们可以摆脱指标的有用的东西
tool like my commerce so here I can say
像我的商业工具，在这里我可以说
how long it takes to process a job so a
处理一份工作需要多长时间
transform photo job and here I can do I
转换照片工作，在这里我可以做
can provide tags you know I can do it if
可以提供您知道我可以做到的标签
I want but I can also say record the the
我想要，但我也可以说记录下
duration right I can give it a duration
持续时间对，我可以给它一个持续时间
I can say record this hard-coded
我可以说录制这个硬编码
duration can be you know 12 milliseconds
持续时间可以知道12毫秒
right I could do a recording with a
对，我可以用
runnable right so something very
可运行的权利，所以非常
convenient convenient ways of getting
便捷便捷的获取方式
that data there I can say you know do
那里的数据我可以说你知道吗
something expensive and slow here if I
如果我在这里有些昂贵和缓慢
want to get the result value if I don't
想获得结果值，如果我不这样做
get the return value out of this
从中得到返回值
processing I'm like system out print
处理我就像系统绝版
hello world let's say instead of
你好，世界，而不是说
printing out the hello world let's say
打个比方说你好世界
that I want to record sorry I want to
我想记录对不起，我想
return hello world instead of doing that
返回你好世界而不是那样做
I can say that I'm gonna use a new a new
我可以说我要使用新的
supplier so a new supplier of type
供应商，所以是新的供应商
string and I'll return hello world and
字符串，我将返回世界
the result is now given back to my
结果现在返回给我
giving back to me here on the a on the
在这里给我回馈
other side so there's the greeting you
另一边，有问候你
know here so feeding tell the world and
知道在这里，所以喂养告诉了世界，
it'll however long it took me to create
我花了很长时间才创建
that I can you know imagine doing some
我可以知道想象做些什么
work or something doing work and then
工作或做某事然后
it'll take some sort of time and then
需要一些时间，然后
that's what's recorded and there's some
那就是记录的，还有一些
you know that's not lots of nice
你知道那不是很好
overloads here that you can use there's
这里可以使用的重载
overloads also for gauges right I
过载也适用于量规
actually showed you how to capture a
确实向您展示了如何捕获
fixed number here but one of the most
这里是固定数字，但最多
interesting ways to capture a gauge is
捕获量规的有趣方法是
to to give it a function right so
赋予它正确的功能
instead of me giving you a giving a
而不是我给你一个
hard-coded number every time I can just
每次我都可以硬编码的号码
give it a function so that it whenever
给它一个功能，以便每当它
it's asked can produce the latest value
要求可以产生最新的价值
so let's say I have this method let's
所以说我有这个方法
say I have a class you know stateful
说我有一堂你知道有状态的课
slow stateful
慢状态
thing right okay and it has a what's a
没事，它有一个什么
good way let's say I have a number of
好方法，假设我有很多
customers right so public int get
正确的客户，所以public int得到
customers logged in to system right here
客户在这里登录系统
I can retain math dot random is going to
我可以保留随机的数学点
be the times a thousand whatever I'm
无论我是几千倍
just producing some random data here so
只是在这里产生一些随机数据
int or even better yet that's just do
诠释甚至更好，但那只是做
new random dot next int alright and can
新的随机点next int好了，可以
I do that is that a is that a rebound I
我就是那个篮板
think so let's say I have this beam have
想想，所以说我有这个光束
a type of slow stateful thing somewhere
一种缓慢的有状态的东西
and I know that I can ask it for how
我知道我可以问它如何
many customers I have customers I have
我有很多顾客我有顾客
in the system right so customer service
在系统中，这样客户服务
new slow stateful thing and now later on
新的缓慢的有状态的事情，现在以后
I'm gonna have a gauge that keeps track
我要有一个可以跟踪的量规
of that for me so I can say gauge
对我来说，所以我可以说
customers logged in pass in a pointer to
登录的客户传递指向
customer service and give it a new to
客户服务，并给它一个新的
double function and here I just say
双重功能，在这里我只是说
that's call customer service dot get
这就是所谓的客户服务点获取
customers logged in so I actually have
客户已登录，所以我实际上有
this convenient little lambda I'm
我是这个方便的小lambda
actually giving a pointer to whatever
实际上给任何东西一个指针
it's gonna keep that reference for me
它会留给我参考
and it'll pass it as a argument that I
并将其作为参数传递给我
can use in this lambda and then I can
可以在此lambda中使用，然后我可以
use that so I can say slow slow
用它，所以我可以说慢慢
right that's what's actually what I've
对，这就是我所拥有的
been given in this case and of course
在这种情况下，当然
this could be a method reference and I
这可能是方法参考，我
could just say so you know here's the
可以说，所以你知道这是
pointer to the source of the stateful
指向有状态源的指针
thing with that pointer call get
那个指针调用得到的东西
customers logged into the system and the
客户登录系统后，
cord that value so it's gonna whenever
记录该值，以便无论何时何地
it needs that number whenever it's
每当它需要它的时候
trying to publish or synchronize these
尝试发布或同步这些
metrics to our back-end registry it'll
后端注册表的指标
you know it'll call that for us we don't
你知道这会叫我们，我们不会
have to constantly contribute to it so
必须不断为此做出贡献
if we have some things that are just
如果我们有一些只是
kind of off in their own updating their
在自己更新自己的那种关闭
own state then this is a great way to
自己的状态，那么这是一种很棒的方法
sort of capture that okay so I'm out of
可以的捕捉，所以我不在了
different overloads you a lot of very
不同会使您超负荷
convenient ways of thinking about the
方便的思考方式
metrics now let's go ahead and use this
指标，现在让我们继续使用
all in terms of spring boot okay so
所有的 spring boot 都可以
let's go ahead and bring back spring
让我们继续前进，带回 Spring
boot
开机
and look at what spring Booga gives us
看看 Spring 的Booga给了我们什么
we have now just a you know very basic
我们现在只有一个，您知道非常基本的
spring good application
Spring 良好的应用
all right good very good and I'm gonna
好的，很好，我要
create a simple beam that's an
创建一个简单的光束
application runner that's going to take
需要的应用程序运行程序
advantage of a executor service
遗嘱执行人服务的优势
scheduled executor service and it's
预定的执行人服务，
going to be executors that's new
将成为新的执行人
schedule thread pool one and well use
安排线程池一并很好地使用
that will say return args and we're
那会说返回参数，我们
gonna use that to schedule some work so
会用来安排一些工作，所以
this dot scheduled a fixed rate and I'm
这个圆点预定了固定汇率，我是
going to create a new Rena bowl and
要创建一个新的Rena碗，
we're gonna run it every 500
我们要每500个运行一次
milliseconds using you know with a with
以毫秒为单位使用
a gap in between five millisecond so
五毫秒之间的间隔
it'll start off after 500 milliseconds
它会在500毫秒后开始
and it'll then run every five
然后每五个运行一次
milliseconds and if this you know if
毫秒，如果知道的话
this takes if this you know takes a
如果你知道这需要一个
let's say 600 milliseconds then indeed
假设确实有600毫秒
the second one will start before the
第二个将在
first one has finished so it if you're
第一个已经完成，所以如果你
doing a fixed rate then you want to make
做一个固定的利率，那么你想
sure that you finish you don't want to
确保完成您不想
get it all bunched up on itself right
让一切都自己堆砌起来
now you can do scheduled at a fixed it's
现在您可以按固定的时间安排
gonna move fixed delay rate I think it's
要移动固定延迟率，我认为是
I think the delay when is there is the
我认为延迟时间是
one that avoids they you know it gets
一种避免他们知道的方法
stagger trying to get staggered out so
试图错开
that one finishes before the next one
一个在下一个之前完成
starts so you want to be be aware of the
开始，所以您想知道
difference there I think I have the
差异，我想我有
right I have the right one in this case
对，在这种情况下，我有对的
but in our case it doesn't really matter
但就我们而言，这并不重要
we're just gonna publish a metric so we
我们只是要发布一个指标，所以我们
have something to work with so what I'm
有什么可以合作的，所以我
gonna do is I'm going to publish a
我要做的是发布一个
metric here using the meter registry so
此处使用仪表注册表进行度量
I'll inject that in here
我在这里注入
and we don't have to configure right
而且我们不必配置正确的
that's a nice thing it's a it's it's
这是一件好事，这是
spring boot of course so the spring
spring boot 当然是 Spring
boots automatically can configure a
启动时可以自动配置
composite meter registry which itself
复合仪表注册中心本身
has access to the DMX and Prometheus
有权使用DMX和Prometheus
meter registers and that all is done for
计价器，一切都完成了
us automatically thanks to the presence
我们自动感谢的存在
of these libraries on the crafts baptism
这些图书馆对手工艺品的洗礼
these dependencies so now we can say
这些依赖关系，所以我们现在可以说
meet a registry and what I wanna do
遇到注册表，我想做什么
someone use a timer okay so I'm gonna
有人使用计时器好吧，我要
create a timer let's say I'm doing some
创建一个计时器，假设我正在做一些
sort of job that takes some time so
这项工作需要一些时间，所以
transform photo task okay and I want to
转换照片任务好了，我想
record a magistrate metric
记录裁判指标
over here so I'm gonna say that I want
在这里，我要说我想要
to record iteration to iteration of
记录迭代
milliseconds since I'm going to give it
自从我要给它以来的毫秒数
some milliseconds and I'm gonna you know
几毫秒，我会知道
I suppose like it just to this randomly
我想只是喜欢这个
so a new random thought next int and
所以下一个新的随机思想int和
what is the inside the int is the upper
int的内部是什么
bound is that right next int is that the
必然是下一个int是
seed no it's not it's um so what do I do
种子不，不是吗，所以我该怎么办
I want to just multiply it so into our
我想将其乘以
equals
等于
okay I guess I can just to map that
好吧，我想我可以将其映射
random just to be sure so math dot
只是为了确保随机点
random times a thousand all right so I'm
一千次随机好吧，我是
gonna save all of that and we'll say a
要保存所有这些，我们会说
long long R and I'll give it a long okay
很长很长R，我会好好考虑的
are so sleep okay so I'm gonna say that
睡得好，所以我要说
this job is taking so many seconds I've
这项工作花了我很多秒钟
got this is a millisecond so maybe it
这是毫秒，所以也许
should be um you know it's not a very
应该是嗯，你知道这不是一个非常
lot it's not a lot of time either way
两种方式都不是很多时间
but whatever will have some number
但无论有多少
presumably greater than zero and that's
大概大于零，那是
been a less than a thousand and we're
不到一千，我们
gonna sleep we're gonna have that win a
要睡觉，我们要赢得胜利
register different timings that that
记录不同的时间
reflect this duration okay it's
反映这个持续时间好吗
artificial because I don't I don't
人造的，因为我不，我不
actually sit here and wait that long and
其实坐在这里等那么久
there's my updated code now this is
现在有我的更新代码
gonna run it's gonna register matrix I'm
要运行它将注册矩阵
gonna see that met those metrics
会看到满足那些指标
reflected in the running system so
反映在正在运行的系统中
that's one option
那是一种选择
I want to see this information in the
我想在
application that's been good application
很好的应用程序
as part of the that's part of the
作为那部分的一部分
actuator so I'm gonna go ahead and say I
执行器，所以我要继续说
want to expose all of the metrics all
想要公开所有指标
the endpoints all the actuator in place
端点将所有执行器安装到位
I could just say show me the health
我只能说告诉我健康
comma metrics but I want to show all of
逗号指标，但我想显示所有
them and then I'll restart the
他们，然后我将重新启动
application with this code in place
带有此代码的应用程序
and we'll see that spring boot does all
我们会看到Spring Boot可以完成所有工作
the work for us right we've already got
对我们来说，我们已经拥有的工作
this endpoint up and running so
该端点正常运行
localhost:8080 for sash actuator and we
本地主机：8080用于窗扇执行器，我们
go there we can see a number of
去那里，我们可以看到一些
different end points and that's a you
不同的终点，那就是你
know we can have a whole other show on
知道我们可以在其他节目上
these different end points but let's
这些不同的终点，但让我们
look at the metrics endpoint here click
在这里查看指标端点
on metrics and we can see all these
在指标上，我们可以看到所有这些
different metrics that have been
不同的指标
calculated
计算的
you know computed for us automatically
你知道会自动为我们计算
by spring boot things like the log back
在 spring boot 之前，像重新登录一样
events the jvm information information
事件jvm信息信息
by the way that was inspired by for
受到的启发
example what the the The Spectator
观众的例子
library for Netflix at less than someone
Netflix的图书馆数量少于某人
does behind the scenes so all this stuff
确实在幕后，所以所有这些东西
is like you know battle-tested you know
就像你知道经过考验的你知道
field-tested techniques for getting
经过现场测试的技术
insight into what the JVM is doing all
洞悉JVM在做什么
that is reflected here and we have
这反映在这里，我们有
things like the Tomcat State the JVM
Tomcat之类的东西
threads liveliness little castles loaded
线程生动活泼的小城堡装
and unloaded their Kartik RCP
并卸载了他们的Kartik RCP
connections cache access ease you know
连接缓存访问方便您知道
all the kind of stuff that you would
所有你想要的东西
want including our custom metric which
想要包括我们的自定义指标
is transform photo tasks and if we look
是转换照片任务，如果我们看
at this you notice that this endpoint is
此时，您注意到该端点是
a little different than what we had
与我们所拥有的有些不同
before and spring boot 1.5 so again oh
之前和 spring boot 1.5如此再次哦
what's happening in spring would I knows
我知道 Spring 会发生什么
we've we've you know deprecated the
我们已经知道您已弃用
counter service and the gauge service
柜台服务和仪表服务
and all those things from from the
以及所有来自
spring boot 1.1 X that's all gone you
spring boot 1.1 X一切都荡然无存
can use micrometer instead that's a we
可以用千分尺代替
consider that a superset a superseding
认为超集是取代
sort of introduction that said we don't
有些介绍说我们不
we don't you know we don't want people
我们不知道我们不想要人
to feel like they have to jump to to
觉得他们必须跳到
don't know to be able to use micrometer
不知道能用千分尺
so there is a bridge library that you
所以有一个桥库
can use with spring boot 1x that will
可以与 spring boot 1x一起使用
allow you to use micrometer in those
允许您在其中使用千分尺
older environments and it's also you
较旧的环境，也是你
know it's important understand that
知道重要的是要了解
while we're no longer you know we don't
虽然我们不再，你知道我们不
particularly mend drop was their metrics
特别是下降的是他们的指标
anymore we still use it in some cases so
在某些情况下我们仍然使用它，因此
I did mention them that some systems
我确实提到了一些系统
lend themselves better to uh to
更适合自己
hierarchical information and one of us
分层信息和我们之一
jmx so actually if you look at this
jmx所以实际上，如果你看这个
MX meter registry behind-the-scenes this
MX Meter注册表的后台
is using the drop reserved meter meter
正在使用下降预留仪表
registry and it's using the DMX reporter
注册表，它正在使用DMX报告程序
so you know a lot of different adapters
所以你知道很多不同的适配器
here this in this case since it since
在这种情况下，因为
it's a hierarchical registry JMX is and
这是JMX的分层注册表，并且
it doesn't have support for dimensional
它不支持尺寸
metrics anyway
无论如何指标
why bother reinventing and right so we
为什么要重新发明，对，所以我们
just use what works and that's why we
只需使用有效的方法，这就是为什么我们
get this nice support there so now we
得到很好的支持，所以现在我们
have this information indium in the
在该信息中有铟
output here and we can look at the
输出在这里，我们可以看看
details here right so even though the
详细信息在这里，即使
endpoint is different you can still get
端点不同，您仍然可以获得
the details but you have to drill down
详细信息，但您必须深入了解
the reason you have to drill down is
您必须向下钻取的原因是
because there are different dimensions
因为有不同的尺寸
all right so here's there's no tags in
好的，所以这里没有标签
this one but let's go look at one that
这个，但让我们来看一个
most assuredly does have tags which is
最肯定的是有标签是
to say how many HTTP requests do we have
说我们有多少个HTTP请求
so HTTP server requests now this metric
因此HTTP服务器现在请求此指标
isn't going to be all that useful yet
不会那么有用
right so it's a HTTP server requests
对，所以这是一个HTTP服务器请求
click on that and you can see that
点击那个，你可以看到
there's only been a few different
只有几个不同
endpoints that we've called but you know
我们称为端点，但您知道
and we can see the things like account
我们可以看到帐户
the total time and the max of any
总时间和最大值
particular request all that is reflected
特别要求所有反映
here in the statistics that are at the
在统计中
top but we also have these different
顶部，但我们也有这些不同
tags these different dimensions that we
标记这些不同的尺寸，我们
can use to drill down so we can say I
可以用来向下钻取，所以我们可以说我
want to find all requests that were HT
想要查找所有属于HT的请求
of type H to begin all right so you can
H类型的开始就可以了，所以您可以
say a tag equals method equals key and
说标签等于方法等于键，
it'll show you only this request well of
它只会向您显示此请求
course in this case I didn't when you
当然在这种情况下我没有当你
buy us anything since all requests are
向我们购买任何东西，因为所有要求都是
get but uh you know you can see how
得到，但是你知道你可以看到
useful that would be to be able to drill
有用的是能够钻
down by tag in that way but key value by
以这种方式按标签向下，但按键值
status right or by a but keen key value
地位或关键价值
and key and value right these pairs you
以及键和值对这些对您
can drill down by status for example if
可以按状态下钻，例如
there is a 404 is it 200 it's address so
地址是404是200
you can do complex queries and this is
您可以执行复杂的查询，这是
just the actuator in point right we time
只是我们时刻的执行器
series databases you know tools like
您知道的系列数据库工具
Prometheus will do a far better job of
普罗米修斯会做得更好
sort of visualizing this information so
可视化此信息，以便
let's talk about that let's let's look
让我们来谈谈，让我们来看看
at Prometheus which I have running in
在我曾经参加过的普罗米修斯
the background here in port 1990 and
1990年港口的背景和
Prometheus is one of a sort of a new
普罗米修斯是一种新的
breed of
品种
time-series databases this one I think
我认为时间序列数据库
came out of soundcloud.com it's a you
从soundcloud.com出来是你
know battle-tested works at scale we
知道我们经过大规模测试的作品
know it works well and Netflix out this
知道它运作良好，而Netflix就是这么做的
is another one that's come out of
是另一个出来的
Netflix so we know again that one works
Netflix，所以我们再次知道一个可行
well as well so a lot of different too
以及很多不同的地方
designed to solve this problem well and
旨在很好地解决这个问题，
this one has got a very very
这个有一个非常非常
sophisticated graphing subsystem as does
复杂的图形子系统
Atlas so here we can look at the
图集，所以在这里我们可以看一下
information related to the transformed
与转换有关的信息
photo task and if we look at that we can
摄影任务，如果我们看一下，我们可以
see transform transform photo task did
看到变换照片任务了吗
that code is that not happening every
该代码是不会发生
500 tasks
500个任务
Prometheus transform photo test service
普罗米修斯变换照片测试服务
so count for example execute you can see
所以算一下执行，你可以看到
that right now there are no there's no
那现在没有没有
you know there's no differences here in
你知道这里没有区别
the data it's always just one graph it's
数据永远只是一张图
just one trend line let's reduce the
一条趋势线让我们减少
window here quite a bit
这里的窗户很多
so you can see the stair steps here I
所以你可以在这里看到楼梯的台阶
just did it for the last minute and all
在最后一分钟才做了
the different examples stair step there
不同的例子楼梯在那里
are now five minutes now I want to I
现在是五分钟我想我
want to you know have different
想知道你有不同
dimensions here so let's go ahead and
尺寸在这里，让我们继续
change this data one thing you know one
更改此数据一件事你知道的一件事
thing you can do to change this date of
您可以更改此日期的操作
course is to contribute a a timer using
当然是使用
this this meter this meter registry
这个水表这个水表注册表
thing here right this is a convenient
这里的东西很方便
way to do it but there's also these
做到的方式，但也有这些
builds are api's right so you have these
api是正确的版本，因此您拥有这些
builder api's and you can use those to
生成器api，您可以使用它们来
do you know to build up more complex
你知道要建立更复杂的吗
kinds of contributions to the tomb you
对坟墓的种种贡献
know registry so I can actually say can
知道注册表，所以我可以说可以
say a timer dot builder dot transform
说一个计时器点生成器点转换
photo tasks I can say that I want to
摄影任务我可以说我想
support a duration the duration or an
支持持续时间或持续时间
SLA that were you know it says of
您知道的SLA涉及
milliseconds is one going all the way up
毫秒是一路上升
to of seconds to ten so I want to say I
几秒到十秒，所以我想说
want to support that SLA between those
想要支持那些之间的SLA
two I want to support publishing
两个我要支持发布
percentile histograms I want to have
我想拥有的百分比直方图
custom tags here and the tags are you
自定义标签在这里，标签就是你
know I could I could configure this per
知道我可以配置每个
metric here I could certainly do that
我在这里可以肯定地做到这一点
right that's a good idea actually we can
对，这是一个好主意，实际上我们可以
do that as well so we could let's
也这样做，所以我们可以
publish the tag here but let's say
在此处发布标签，但可以说
publish the tag of what what is it tag
发布什么是标签的标签
the tag will be something that will
标签将是将
check because it's gonna be variable
检查，因为它会可变
right well we'll do something different
好吧，我们会做一些不同的事情
here so um you know JPEG format Ryan it
在这里，所以你知道JPEG格式Ryan
can be format math.random greater than
的格式可以为math.random大于
0.5 you know PNG hopefully it's a few if
0.5你知道PNG希望是
the open web is anything otherwise a jpg
开放的网络不是jpg
right and so there we are so there's my
对，所以我们就在那里，有我的
custom tag and I'll record it register
自定义标签，我将其记录为注册
it rather with the meeting registry
而不是会议注册表
there and then we record it so that's my
在那里，然后我们记录下来，这就是我的
custom
习俗
to metric and I can I can you know I can
以公制为单位，我可以吗？
do all sorts of very dynamic things with
用...做各种非常动态的事情
these builders there's equivalents for
这些建设者有相当于
the counters and for the gauges and
柜台和仪表和
there are even some kinds of meters that
甚至还有一些仪表
are not available from the meter
仪表不可用
registry interface that you can also
注册表界面，您也可以
contribute that are just sort of not
贡献一点
standard they're not common enough that
他们不是很普遍
we can guarantee them across all
我们可以保证他们在所有
different support interfaces so there's
不同的支持界面，因此
also for example long timer or long task
也例如长时间计时器或长时间任务
timers right a long test timer is like a
计时器很长的测试计时器就像
timer except that it's meant to have a
计时器，除了它有一个
deadline it's meant to have a time at
截止日期，这意味着有时间
which point the system should do
系统应该做什么
alerting to say that this has exceeded
提醒说这已经超出
some sort of deadline so think about a
某种截止日期，所以考虑一下
timer the timer is great for small
计时器适合小型
duration jobs like like like resizing a
持续性工作，例如调整大小
photo for example well if I have a long
好吧，如果我有很长的照片
task timer maybe I'm processing a you
任务计时器，也许我正在处理你
know several gigs are terabytes of data
知道几个演出是TB级的数据
whatever the job is supposed to just
无论工作本来应该
take you know 10 minutes whatever and
大概要花10分钟
you expect on average it'll take 10
您预计平均需要10
minutes but somebody for some reason
分钟，但由于某种原因有人
it's running for three hours well would
它已经运行了三个小时
you like to find out that that system
您想找出那个系统
has run over by two hours and 50 minutes
已经用了两个小时零五十分钟
after the fact or would you like to find
在事实或您想找到之后
out as it's going over that that that
结束那件事
allotted schedule and so a long test
分配的时间表和如此长的考验
timer can publish you know sort of a
计时器可以发布您知道的某种
back-channel
反向通道
notification telling you that something
通知告诉您某事
is wrong I can do and these a lot of
我做错了，这些很多
these different times these databases
这些不同的时间这些数据库
will support alerting based on that
将支持基于
deadline about that on that kind of
关于那种截止日期
custom deadline on the right so you you
正确的自定义截止日期，让您
can use that as well you should use that
也可以使用它
for longer longer jobs but not all
对于更长的更长的工作，但不是全部
systems support that so we don't support
系统支持，因此我们不支持
that we don't surface that in the need a
我们不会在需要中浮出水面
registry interface there right so you
注册表界面在那里，所以你
have a lot of different options here now
现在这里有很多不同的选择
I showed you how to register a tag here
我告诉你如何在这里注册标签
right and earlier we looked at it's go
对，我们早先看过了
ahead we start this and get some traffic
提前，我们开始这个并获得一些流量
in the meantime earlier we looked at how
在此之前，我们研究了
we can configure things with the config
我们可以使用config进行配置
method in the meter registry and that's
仪表注册表中的方法，那就是
sort of an option and you can actually
一种选择，您实际上可以
you can get access to that meter
您可以使用该仪表
registry while things are being created
创建事物时注册
before any metrics have been contributed
在任何指标被贡献之前
using a meter registry customizer and
使用电表注册表定制器和
this is a callback interface that gives
这是一个回调接口
you a pointer to the registry before any
您之前任何指向注册表的指针
meters have been added to the
米已添加到
application that we've added to the
我们已添加到
meter industry so here I can say Richie
仪表行业，所以在这里我可以说Richie
duck config common tags and I couldn't
鸭配置常用标签，我不能
say region is going to be equal to you
说地区将等于你
know let's say it's
知道让我们说这是
let's say inject the region and so some
假设注入该区域，等等
sort of global configuration that's
某种全局配置
unique to this node so I'll say string
该节点唯一的，所以我将说字符串
region here I'll say it's gonna be your
我会说这是你的地区
region or US west okay so I'm going to
地区或美国西部还可以，所以我要去
use US West as the default value if the
如果将“美国西部”用作默认值，
environment variable region doesn't
环境变量区域不
exist and of course in this case it
存在，当然在这种情况下
doesn't exist so it'll always just be us
不存在，所以它永远只是我们
West for this case and you know that's a
西方在这种情况下，你知道那是一个
very clean way to configure common
很普通的配置方式
things that across all the different all
跨越所有不同事物的事物
the different metrics there another
另一个不同的指标
thing that you can do very nicely you
你可以做得很好的事情
know common another way to change the
知道另一种改变
default behavior is to configure custom
默认行为是配置自定义
properties so I have here for example
属性，所以我在这里例如
the management that metrics that enabled
衡量指标的管理层
thought I can say all equals false and
以为我可以说所有等于假，
if I do that all is a special keyword
如果我这样做，那都是一个特殊的关键字
here it'll disable the publication and
在这里它将禁用发布，并且
accumulation of all metrics not just
不仅是所有指标的累积
ones that I'm cutting but all of them in
我正在切割的那些，但都在
the system I can use like I can say
我可以说的我可以使用的系统
everything that starts with JVM will be
以JVM开头的一切都会
disabled if I do this right everything
如果我这样做对所有人都禁用
JVM got food at bar everything that
JVM阻碍了一切
starts with JVM will be disabled
从JVM开始将被禁用
including JVM got food at bar so I can
包括JVM在内，我可以
also disable for example HTTP right if I
如果我也禁用例如HTTP权限
wanted to so you can do some very kind
想这样做，你可以做一些非常友好的
of interesting white lit white listing
有趣的白色点亮的白色列表
or white labeling or no sorry white
或白色标签或不对不起白色
listing or a variables for example of
清单或变量，例如
properties you can also configure custom
您还可以配置自定义属性
filters and custom configurations so I
过滤器和自定义配置，所以我
can actually say that I want for HTTP
可以说我想要HTTP
server requests I want to have a
服务器请求我想要一个
percentiles I want to I want to capture
我要捕获的百分位数
distributions of present house and I
现在的房子和我的分布
want to do that for 0.5 and point nine
想要以0.5为目标并指向9
five all right so I can actually
五好吧，我可以
configure that for them for that metric
为他们配置该指标
friend you can do this in properties in
朋友，您可以在
a generic way across all things but you
除您之外的所有事物的通用方法
can also do kinds of these kinds of
也可以做这样的事情
custom configurations using a meter
使用仪表自定义配置
filter so here's a meter filter and a
过滤器，所以这是一个仪表过滤器和一个
meter filter is just that it's a filter
仪表过滤器只是它是一个过滤器
that gets processed it gets a chance to
得到处理的机会
run or it gets a look at every ministry
运行，或者看看每个部委
every metric that gets sampled or
采样的每个指标或
captured and in
捕获并进入
it's given a chance to decide whether
有机会决定是否
that metric gets to be retained or if
该指标将被保留，或者
it's just ignored basically and when I
它基本上被忽略了，当我
say ignored it means it's not collected
说被忽略，表示未收集
it's not published to the time series
它没有发布到时间序列
database or just a monitoring system
数据库或只是监视系统
it's just kind of ignored so I can
这只是一种忽略，所以我可以
actually be as granular as the one here
实际上和这里的一样细
I could say I want to accept you know
我可以说我想接受你知道
anything that starts with JVM that's
任何以JVM开头的
example that we had earlier
我们之前的例子
so anything if the name starts with JVM
如果名称以JVM开头，那么一切
ignore it but otherwise let everything
忽略它，否则让一切
go through so if we look at our metrics
仔细检查一下指标
in point I haven't we started the app
我还没有启动应用程序
right now so if you look at the metrics
现在，如果您查看指标
endpoint here we can see JVM like a lot
在这里的端点，我们可以看到很多JVM
of them a lot of them there start with
他们很多在那里开始
the token JVM let's go back and add this
令牌JVM让我们返回并添加它
simple meter filter while we start the
启动时，简单的仪表过滤器
application and you know more JVM right
应用程序，您会了解更多关于JVM的知识
it's all gone the those metrics are just
这些指标全都消失了
completely gone and they're not being
完全消失了，他们没有被
published to this either so that's a
发表于此，所以这是一个
that's very convenient you can do all
那很方便，你可以做所有的事情
sorts of interesting things with meter
仪表有趣的事情
filters here you can even compose and
过滤器，您甚至可以撰写和
become create composite meter filters
成为创建复合仪表过滤器
and and so on or just read your register
等等，或者只是阅读您的注册表
a bunch of the rich one so okay so we've
一堆有钱的人，好吧，我们已经
got now a number of different ways to
现在有许多不同的方法
change application to change the
更改应用程序以更改
defaults the meter registry customizers
默认为电表注册表定制器
are going to be the the the most useful
将是最有用的
way we also have something called a
我们也有一个叫做
meter binder meter binder is a interface
仪表活页夹仪表活页夹是一个接口
that when spring mood sees it it's part
当 Spring 的心情出现时，这是一部分
of the micrometer API but spring boot
千分尺API的外观，但Spring 启动
knows about it and you get a you're
知道这一点，你得到一个你是
given a pointer to the registry and you
给了注册表的指针，你
can have interface you can have objects
可以有接口，可以有对象
that know how to unpack information to
知道如何解压信息
extract useful metrics from a different
从不同的地方提取有用的指标
subsystem and contribute contribute them
子系统并贡献他们
to to the route to the registries right
到通往注册表的路线的权利
and so here you might you might have
所以在这里您可能会拥有
like a something that knows about data
就像了解数据的东西一样
sources as spring boot does right
spring boot 做的正确来源
there's actually a data source pool
实际上有一个数据源池
metrics object and it implements meter
指标对象并实现仪表
binder it's given a callback to this
活页夹它对此进行了回调
meter registry and it's also given a
仪表注册表，它也给了
it's also found out it's also discovered
它也被发现它也被发现
all of the other data source connection
所有其他数据源连接
pools in the application context so it's
在应用程序上下文中池，因此
it's using the it's using the fact that
它使用的是事实
it's got access to both registry and
可以同时访问注册表和
the data sources to contribute some
数据源贡献了一些
metrics to the meter registry that will
计量表注册表的指标
get updated whenever the state of the of
每当的状态更新时
the connection pulse changes right so
连接脉冲改变正确，所以
this is a good way if you want to
这是一个很好的方法，如果您想
contribute metrics a whole you know a
全面了解您知道的指标
whole suite of metrics and you've got
整套指标，您已经
some system that need some subsystem
一些需要子系统的系统
that needs to be monitored or measured
需要监视或测量的
you could do that in a single place and
你可以在一个地方做
then reuse that somebody else can just
然后重用别人可以
install the meter binder and the
安装仪表活页夹和
application context and it'll do all the
应用程序上下文，它将完成所有
work for you or you could put it in Auto
为您工作，或者您可以将其置于“自动”状态
configuration right that's a very common
这是很常见的配置权限
use case here is to have this do the
这里的用例是这样做
right thing out of the box is you know I
开箱即用的正确事情是你知道我
could write an auto configuration that
可以写一个自动配置，
has custom meter binders I can have a
有定制的活页夹，我可以有一个
Auto configuration that has a meter
具有仪表的自动配置
registry customizer and some meter
注册表定制器和一些仪表
filters and you know you know when it
过滤器，您知道何时知道
when somebody I had that application to
当有人向我提出申请
the classpath you know we're
你知道我们在
automatically making sure to measure the
自动确保测量
things that as an organization you have
作为组织所拥有的东西
you decided you want to measure so that
您决定要测量，以便
get to consistency and you get a
保持一致性，您将获得
velocity to a consistency right this is
速度达到一致性，这是
why again it also helps to have the
为什么又可以帮助拥有
support at the platform levels and so
在平台级别的支持等
clad fun day for example well see that
例如，穿好衣服的日子很好看
you're using micrometer and it'll auto
您正在使用千分尺，它将自动
reconfigure your meter registry to point
重新配置您的电表注册表
to the platform meter registry if you
到平台计量器注册表
want it to right so a lot of them a lot
希望它正确很多，很多
of value in having this stuff permeate
这些东西渗透的价值
all your code and just be something that
您所有的代码，只是
just works it's just it's just
只是工作而已
everything knows about it knows how to
一切都知道它知道如何
use it and so on right and it's a very
使用它，以此类推，这是一个非常
lightweight library so it doesn't cost
轻量级的库，因此无需花费
you anything to to do that okay so now
你有什么事情要做，所以现在
we've got this custom metric we got this
我们有这个自定义指标
timer it's calculating data it's been
计时器正在计算数据
running in the background now so let's
现在在后台运行，让我们
go to our Prometheus and what do we say
去我们的普罗米修斯，我们怎么说
this was this is called this is called
这就是所谓的这叫做
transform photo task
转换照片任务
alright so transform photo task count
好吧，所以转换照片任务计数
and you can see there's now four
你会看到现在有四个
different time series in there broken
那里不同的时间序列坏了
down by the format alright and the
向下按格式，然后
region right so you can see it says
正确的区域，所以您可以看到它说
region is equal to us west and region is
地区等于我们西部，地区等于
equal to us well of course that's hard
当然等于我们好难
to code it there so we have all these
在那里编码，所以我们拥有所有这些
different values here and we can we can
这里有不同的值，我们可以
look at specific sections of them to see
看他们的特定部分，看看
some specific dimensions if you well so
如果可以的话，一些特定的尺寸
we can say I'm regen equals us West well
可以说，我的康复等于我们的西部
of course that's same as that's two of
当然，这是两个相同的
them right that's
他们是对的
kind of identity we can also say I want
我们也可以说我想要那种身份
to look at everything it kind of equals
看一切都相等
so I can say like this I can do a
所以我可以这样说
regular expression dot query enter
正则表达式点查询输入
execute or not give me that of course in
执行或不给我那个
this case is everything but you might
这种情况就是一切，但你可能会
have metrics from different regions that
具有来自不同地区的指标
are all accumulated in this in this
都积累在这个
output here so I would show you all that
输出在这里，所以我会告诉你所有
all the metrics that are of the form
所有形式的指标
transform photo task second count and it
转换照片任务的第二计数，然后
would show you all those that are in the
会向您显示所有在
US but this would ignore for example all
美国，但是这会忽略所有
those that are coming from Asia for
那些来自亚洲的
example or whatever right you could have
示例或您可能拥有的任何权利
a different metrics in different schema
不同架构中的不同指标
there you can use regular freshness to
在那里，您可以使用常规的新鲜度
describe that you can do negation so I
描述你可以做否​​定，所以我
can say you know not equal to us West
可以说你知道不等于我们西部
all right execute that and that gives me
好吧，执行那个，那给了我
these two right this is a I guess these
这两个对，这是一个我猜这些
are the ones that don't match that we
是那些与我们不匹配的
can also do format does not equal PNG
也可以做格式不等于PNG
right so that is that so this is the
对，就是这样，这就是
data that corresponds to jpg right so
对应于jpg的数据
you know you can do very complex
你知道你可以做的很复杂
clearing here you can create lots of
在这里清理，您可以创建很多
different graphs as well like this and
像这样的不同图和
and visualize them over the system over
并通过系统将它们可视化
the time and put some some sort of
时间，并投入一些
monitor the system somewhere in your
在您的某处监视系统
organization so and then use it to drive
这样组织，然后用它来驱动
use it to drive you know a screen for
用它来驱动你知道的屏幕
example a marker or Society or alerting
例如标记或协会或警报
even better so we have now a you know a
甚至更好，所以我们现在有一个，你知道一个
we've gone very very very briefly over a
我们已经非常非常非常简短地讨论了
number of features in my kamar we've
我的kamar中的功能数量
looked at it's a you know smart
看着那是你知道的聪明
automatic collection of metrics for you
自动为您收集指标
for things like data source utilization
用于数据源利用
rather than queue connection file
而不是队列连接文件
descriptor usage log back events uptime
描述符使用率日志回事件正常运行时间
and Tom Kent usage CPU usage and spring
和Tom Kent使用CPU使用率和spring
ABC and web flux request lightning tease
ABC和网络通量要求闪电逗
we've looked at you know it can support
我们已经看过您知道它可以支持
things like rest template Layton sees
休息模板Layton看到的东西
we've also got support for capturing JVM
我们还支持捕获JVM
metrics including utilization of various
指标包括各种利用率
memory buffer pools statistics related
内存缓冲池相关统计信息
to garbage collection thread utilization
垃圾回收线程利用率
numbers of classes loaded and unloaded
加载和卸载的类数
we've looked at the basic API for
我们已经看过了
micrometer starting with the meter
千分尺从仪表开始
registry and branching out to look at
注册表并扩展以查看
the gauges timers and
仪表计时器和
and counters we looked at how it all
和柜台，我们看着这一切
plugs into spring boot and of course we
插入 spring boot ，当然我们
looked at some of the automatic support
看了一些自动支持
that we get here for publishing of
我们到这里来出版
metrics now we did so without kind of
指标，我们现在没有这样做
really touching on how spring mood is
真的触动 Spring 的心情
publishing these metrics it's kind of
发布这些指标是一种
interesting that in this case we're
有趣的是，在这种情况下，我们
using Prometheus now Prometheus is a
现在使用Prometheus是Prometheus
pole based you know monitoring system
基于极点的您知道的监控系统
it pulls data from your service your
它从您的服务中提取数据
service has to surface that information
服务必须浮出水面
for it to pull so the spring boot Auto
使其拉动，使 spring boot 自动
configuration here automatically stands
这里的配置自动站立
up a endpoint called actuator Prometheus
称为执行器Prometheus的端点
and this endpoint is in the format that
该端点的格式为
your Prometheus engine is going to
您的Prometheus引擎将
expect to be able to see to be able to
期望能够看到能够
read the data now this endpoint is a you
现在读取数据，此端点是您
know it's strange-looking but this is
知道它看起来很奇怪，但这是
what Prometheus is expecting now if
普罗米修斯现在期望什么
you're using straight micrometer there's
您使用的是直型千分尺
a there's an API there that you can use
有一个您可以使用的API
that will give you a string that all you
那会给你一个字符串，所有的你
have to do is then stand it up as an
然后要做的就是站起来
HTTP endpoint and point Prometheus to it
HTTP端点并将Prometheus指向它
and that'll work but spring boot just
那会起作用，但是 spring boot 只是
does all that for you right so it's
为您做所有这一切，所以
already done here here for you and then
已经在这里为您完成，然后
you have to configure for me this to be
你必须为我配置
aware of this endpoint so you go for
知道这个端点，所以你去
example to your config file I've got a
你的配置文件的例子，我有一个
config file here localhost 8080 ammo and
配置文件在这里localhost 8080 ammo和
I've configured in my escapes config and
我已经在我的转义配置中配置了
my script configs are there I've got a
我的脚本配置在那里
job job named Springwood actuator
职位名称为Springwood作动器
metrics path equals actuator Prometheus
度量路径等于执行器Prometheus
and the target is this host in port okay
目标是该主机在端口中
so I've got now you know a very simple
所以我现在知道了
configuration file and telling
配置文件并告诉
Prometheus to pull the data from my node
Prometheus从我的节点提取数据
and this is just one instance I could
这只是我可以做的一个例子
have you know five different targets and
你知道五个不同的目标吗？
it would automatically pull the metrics
它会自动提取指标
from all different all five of those now
从所有这五个不同的
this is a this is how you tell
这就是你这样告诉
Prometheus to to read data from my
普罗米修斯从我的读取数据
services on the other hand I might for
另一方面，我可能会为
some other services like graphite I have
我有一些其他服务，例如石墨
to push metrics to it so the client
向其推送指标，以便客户端
that's my micro service would need to
那是我的微服务需要
publish his metrics to graphite and then
将他的指标发布到石墨，然后
graphite has to accumulate and and
石墨必须积累，并且
render them right
使它们正确
there's drawbacks to both sides right in
双方都有弊端
this case if I'm using the pull based
这种情况下，如果我使用基于拉
system then I don't have to have a
系统，那么我不必拥有
custom library that no
自定义库，没有
how to speak to Prometheus in Java this
如何用Java与Prometheus对话
is not a big deal and in most large
没什么大不了的
communities this is not a big deal but
社区这没什么大不了的，但是
perhaps there's no maybe maybe there may
也许没有，也许也许
be a working in language where there
用语言工作
isn't a readily available client library
不是现成的客户端库
so you're kind of on your own to figure
所以你有点自己想
out the protocol to publish metrics to
制定协议以发布指标
to graphite well it turns out that
石墨化的事实证明
graphite uses some stats deep Mayan
石墨使用一些深度玛雅统计数据
Steph sees a or supports density and so
Steph看到或支持密度，因此
Steph sees a super easy protocol but
Steph看到了一个超级简单的协议，但
even there there's there's a number of
即使那里有很多
different flavors of it there's data dog
它的不同口味有数据狗
there's Etsy I mean there's a lot of
有Etsy，我的意思是
different ways to get stats D data staff
获取统计数据D数据人员的不同方法
C flavors and you know you have to
C口味，您知道您必须
contend with that when you write a
当你写一个
client to talk to these to talk to these
客户与这些交谈与这些交谈
tools that support this flavor and other
支持这种口味和其他功能的工具
protocol other marketing systems have
其他营销系统具有的协议
protocols that are far more
协议远不止这些
sophisticated or complicated
复杂或复杂
I mean snaps T for example is dead
我的意思是按扣T已死
simple there's not even really a
简单甚至没有
mechanism for security you just have to
安全机制，您只需要
funnel in a token in you have to
在令牌中漏斗
substitute something else that would
用其他东西代替
have been useful in of itself you have
本身就很有用
to replace that and give it use it for a
替换它并给它使用
token right just because there's no
令牌权是因为没有
built-in mechanism for that so if you
内置的机制，所以如果你
had if you're if you're using a language
如果您使用的是语言
and a technology that doesn't have it
和没有它的技术
the ability to talk to that monitoring
与监控对话的能力
system and you need to do anything
系统，您需要做任何事情
sophisticated anything at all really
真正使一切复杂
then then having the requirement to push
然后有要求推
metrics to that system isn't going to be
该系统的指标将不会
great also you can you can overwhelm
太好了，你可以压倒一切
that system you might be able to send
您可能能够发送的系统
too many requests at a time the
一次有太多要求
downstream system would would read the
下游系统将读取
data and it would you know you it would
数据，你会知道吗
try and read it as fast as it could but
尝试尽快阅读它，但是
if you send more than I can handle it's
如果您发送的邮件超出了我的承受能力，
gonna fall over right on the other hand
另一方面会摔倒
in this case the system is doing a poll
在这种情况下，系统正在进行轮询
based you know for Prometheus it's doing
根据您对普罗米修斯的了解，它在做
pole based accumulation of metrics we've
基于极点的指标积累
looked at the metrics you know in the
看了您在
actual end point and we looked at them
实际的终点，我们看着他们
and the Prometheus endpoint that end
和结束的Prometheus端点
point is the end point that Prometheus
终点是普罗米修斯的终点
needs to do its work and it's not such a
需要做它的工作，不是这样的
big deal anybody can speak HTTP right so
任何人都可以说HTTP很重要
almost any language or protocol these
这些几乎任何语言或协议
days will have the ability to stand up
天将有能力站起来
an HTTP endpoint that prometheus can
Prometheus可以的HTTP端点
then use to to glom state about the
然后用来使状态
application not a big deal right that's
应用程序没什么大不了的
very easy it also has the benefit of
很容易，它也有好处
being
存在
dated by prometheus Prometheus isn't
普罗米修斯（Prometheus）过时的普罗米修斯（Prometheus）不是
gonna try and ingest more daily thick
会尝试每天摄取更多
and then it can handle right it's gonna
然后它可以处理正确的
hopefully keep itself alive and you know
希望自己能活着，你知道
stop before it gets overwhelmed so in
在不知所措之前停下来
this respect this is I think a better
这方面，这是我认为更好的
solution for more resilient systems but
适用于更具弹性的系统的解决方案，但
it does mean that each micro service now
这确实意味着现在每个微服务
has to take responsibility for standing
必须承担起责任
up the station PN point so I guess the
向上站PN点，所以我猜
question is do you want to do you want
问题是你想要吗
to take responsibility for configuring
负责配置
the client to publish metrics or do want
客户发布指标或希望
the HTTP endpoint to serve metrics that
HTTP端点以提供以下指标
can then be ingested by some sort of
然后可以通过某种方式摄取
paper either way the code has to do
编写代码的两种方式
something it's just a matter of the
这只是问题
trade-offs you wanna make and the
您想要进行的权衡和
robustness and resilience
坚固性和弹性
characteristics that you're expecting
您期望的特征
from your system all right so we've
从您的系统上可以，所以我们已经
looked at a number of different things
看了很多不同的东西
we've looked at how to configure
我们已经研究了如何配置
application look at all the metrics that
应用程序查看所有的指标
are supported here we looked at a number
支持这里我们看了一些
different ways to configure things
不同的配置方式
including the various callback
包括各种回调
interfaces and also the properties in
接口以及其中的属性
the spring boot we looked at a few of
spring boot ，我们看了一些
the different mute a registry
不同使注册表静音
implementations that we have here on the
我们在这里的实现
classpath and we talked about some that
classpath，我们谈到了一些
we didn't even see on the website for
我们甚至没有在网站上看到
example the one in Cloud Foundry you
例如Cloud Foundry中的一个
know we've just begun to Scott to
知道我们刚刚开始斯科特
service obviously this is a topic that's
服务显然这是一个主题
near and dear to my heart there's a
亲爱的我附近有一个
number of things that you can and should
您可以并且应该做的事情数量
do to support observability in your
支持您的可观察性
organization and micrometer is a really
组织和千分尺是一个真正的
really powerful step in the right
正确的步骤非常有力
direction so with that my friends thank
方向，这样我的朋友谢谢
you so much for watching I hope you got
你这么多看我希望你得到
something out of this and we'll see you
这样的事情，我们会见到你
next time
下次
you
您